sutherlandglobal.com 2019-04-08

# Privacy Policy | Sutherland

###### Last Updated: February 27, 2019

#### Introduction

We at Sutherland Global Services, Inc. and our Affiliated Companies worldwide ("Sutherland" or “Company”) are committed to respecting your online privacy and recognize your need for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable data ("Personal Data") you share with us.

“ **Affiliated Companies** ” means with respect to any specified person or entity, any other person or entity Controlling, Controlled by or under common Control with such entity, where “ **Control** ” with regard to an entity, means the beneficial, equitable or legal ownership, either directly or indirectly, of more than fifty percent (50%) or more of the capital stock (or other ownership interest, if not a corporation) of such entity ordinarily having voting rights, or effective control of the activities of such entity regardless of the percentage of ownership. 

Sutherland’s Privacy Policy outlines how Sutherland collects, uses, shares, and secures your Personal Data. This policy also describes your choices regarding use, access, and correction of Personal Data.

In furtherance of the Sutherland’s commitment to this Policy, Sutherland has certified to adhere to the Privacy Principles set forth in the EU-US Privacy Shield and with the General Data Privacy Regulation regarding Personal Data related to customer, partners or employees of the Company resident in the European Economic Area and processed in support of the Company’s. Company adheres to the Privacy Shield principles as respectively agreed to by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission. With respect to Personal Data received or transferred pursuant to Privacy Shield, Sutherland is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.

For additional details, please refer to the Privacy Shield section of this Policy.

#### Personal Data

Personal Data is any data relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. Your name, address, phone number and bank account number are examples of Personal Data.

#### Personal Data that we process and for what purposes

Sutherland processes your Personal Data to ensure the efficiency and effectivity of Sutherland business relationships, commercial transactions, marketing and employment practices. Processing will always be based on legitimate grounds or your consent.

#### Collection and Use of Personal Data

Sutherland may collect Personal Data (which covers any data that may be used to identify an individual) from you when you visit Sutherland website. The type of Personal Data collected and their Purpose of Use include (but are not limited to) the items outlined in the table below as follows:  

**Personal Data Type Collected** |  **Purpose of Use**  
---|---  
  
**Personal Identification:**

\- Name

\- Home or physical address

\- Email address, phone number, and other contact data

\- National Identification Number

\- DOB

| 

**Performance of a Contract:**

**Commercial Activity:**

Sutherland collect partial or all data for the fulfillment of goods or services

**Employment:**

Sutherland collect this data to comply with employment regulations, for fulfilllment of employment obligations.  
  
**Contact Data:**

\- Address

\- Phone (landline or mobile)

\- Email

\- Emergency Contact(s)

\- Business Contact Data

| 

**Marketing or Legal Obligation:**

**Commercial Activity:**

Sutherland may collect partial or all data for marketing or service updates

**Employment:**

Sutherland collect this data to comply with employment regulations and for the employment contract

**Benefits Data:**

\- Elections & Deduction Amounts

\- Beneficiaries/Dependents

\- Claims Data

| 

**Performance of a Contract:**

**Employment:**

Sutherland will collect this data to process payroll per the employee contract

**Financial Data:**

\- Banking Details

\- Compensation

\- Tax Data

\- Wage Garnishments

\- Credit Card Data

| 

**Performance of a Contract:**

**Commercial Activity:**

Sutherland may collect partial or all data for the payment of our goods or services

**Employment:**

Sutherland will collect this data to process payroll per the employee contract

**Employee Data:**

**-** Employee Agreements & Consent

\- Employment Contracts & Terms and Conditions

\- Performance & Training Documents

\- Disciplinary Documents

\- Family & Health Information

| 

**Employment:**

Sutherland collects this data to ensure compliance with applicable labor laws, fulfillwork obligations, check compliance with company policies, administer benefits, manage careers and perform general HR operations.   
  
**Candidate Data:**

\- Name

\- Home or physical address

\- Email address, phone number

\- CV or Resumes

\- Background check Data

| 

**Employment:**

Sutherland collect this data for the evaluation of employment opportunities  
  
Sutherland does not as a practice collect Personal Data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade-union membership, and the processing of genetic data, biometric data in order to uniquely identify a person or data concerning health or sex life and sexual orientation.

If Sutherland intends to use and transfer of Personal Data for purposes beyond outside of the Sutherland’s commercial or employment obligations for purposes such as marketing or commercial communications, or if Sutherland discloses Personal data to a third party or use of the Personal Data for other purposes other than the purpose than for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you, Sutherland will offer you the opportunity to affirmatively opt in whether you allow your Personal Data to  be disclosed to a third party or to be used for any purposes other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you.

In addition, Sutherland may need to transfer Personal Data within Sutherland or to Sutherland's third-party service providers, across borders, outside of your country or jurisdiction around the world pursuant to our processes.

#### Choice

The choice of whether to provide Personal Data to Sutherland is up to you. The notice Sutherland provides when it collects Personal Data which will assist in how you prefer to allow us to use your Personal Data. When you do not want to provide your Personal Data, you can still visit most of Sutherland's websites; however, please note that you may be unable to access certain options, offers, and services that involve our interaction with you. If you chose to have a relationship with Sutherland, such as a contractual or other business relationship or partnership, Sutherland will naturally continue to contact you in connection with that business relationship.

You may sign-up and consent to receive email or newsletter communications from Sutherland. If you would like to discontinue receiving these communications, you may update your preferences by using the “Unsubscribe” link found in emails or by contacting Sutherland using the information in the “Contact Data” section of this Policy.

#### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

This site uses cookies to store information on your computer. Some are essential to make Sutherland site work; others help Sutherland improve the user experience. A "cookie" is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect data about website activity. Some cookies and other technologies may serve to recall Personal Data previously indicated by a web user. For greater details, please refer to Sutherland [Cookie Policy to learn more](https://www.sutherlandglobal.com/cookie-policy).

If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) or if located in the European Union, click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

#### Log Files

Log files may record data such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; internet service provider, clickstream patterns; the files viewed on Sutherland website (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), referring and exit pages and dates and times that Sutherland site is accessed to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site.

#### Security

Wherever your Personal Data may be held within Sutherland or on its behalf, Sutherland intends to take commercially reasonable and appropriate steps to protect the Personal Data that you share with Sutherland from unauthorized access or disclosure. 

If you have any questions about the security of your Personal Data, you can contact Sutherland at privacy@sutherlandglobal.com.

#### Legal

Sutherland may be required to disclose Personal Data in connection with a lawful request from law enforcement, public authorities, or other national security request.

Sutherland may also disclose your Personal Data as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, when Sutherland believes in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect Sutherland’s rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

#### Data Retention

Sutherland will not store your data longer than necessary for the purpose for which we have processed your data. How long we retain your data depends on the type of data and the purpose for which we process your data.

#### Data Subject Rights

To exercise any of the following rights, please contact us at marketing@sutherlandglobal.com.

#### Right to Request Access

You may request details of Personal Data which Sutherland holds about you. Upon request, Sutherland will provide a copy of such Personal Data within a reasonable timeframe. If you would like a copy of your Personal Data Sutherland maintains, please write to us at marketing@sutherlandglobal.com.

#### Right to Rectification

If you believe that any Personal Data Sutherland is holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact Sutherland as soon as possible, at the address below. Sutherland will promptly correct any Personal Data found to be incorrect.

#### Right to Object

You may choose to object to the collection or use of your Personal Data:

  * whenever data is processed for the legitimate interest of Sutherland
  * whenever data is processed for a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in Sutherland

Please note that your objection may be overridden by the legitimate interests of Sutherland to process and collect your Personal Data.

#### Right to Erasure

To the extent legally permissible, you may be entitled to have certain Personal Data erased in the following circumstances:

  * The Personal Data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or processed
  * You object to the collection or use of your Personal Data and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing thereof
  * The Personal Data has been unlawfully processed
  * The Personal Data has reached the maximum defined retention period to be erased or for compliance with a legal obligation to which Sutherland is subject

#### Right to Restriction of Processing

You may have the right to restrict further processing of your Personal Data in the following situations:

  * You contest the accuracy of the Personal Data
  * The processing of the data is unlawful
  * The Personal Data Sutherland has reached the defined retention period no longer needs the Personal Data for the purposes of the processing, but you require the Personal Data to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims.
  * You object to the processing and the processing of your Personal Data may be restricted pending the verification of the legitimacy of Sutherland’s grounds to override your rights as a data subject.

#### Right to Portability

You have the right to receive your Personal Data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.  Sutherland will assist in the transmission of such data to another entity, upon request, to the extent technically feasible.

#### Sharing with Service Providers

We may share your Personal Data as described, and for the purposes identified, under the “Collection and Use of Personal Data” section above with third-party service providers who provide us services that assist Sutherland in its business activities which may include marketing, advertising our product/service offerings,  customer support, recruiting and management of employee data, payroll support, maintaining and improving our service offerings, and cloud services infrastructure, among other things.  

Service providers provide certain services available on www.sutherlandglobal.com on Sutherland's behalf. Sutherland may provide data, including Personal Data, which Sutherland collects on the web, through third-party service providers to help it deliver programs, products, data, and services. Service providers are also an important means by which Sutherland maintains its website and mailing lists. These service providers are authorized to use your Personal Data only as necessary to provide these services to us.

#### Children's Privacy

Sutherland’s website is a general audience website. Accordingly, Sutherland does not intend to collect Personal Data from anyone Sutherland know to be under 13 years of age.

#### Commitment

Sutherland is committed to privacy. Protecting your privacy online is an evolving area, and this website is constantly evolving to meet these demands.

If you have any comments or questions regarding Sutherland’s Privacy Policy, please contact Sutherland at [privacy@sutherlandglobal.com](mailto:privacy@sutherlandglobal.com).  While Sutherland cannot guarantee privacy perfection, Sutherland will address any issue to the best of its abilities as soon as possible.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

#### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

Sutherland and the following subsidiaries, Sutherland Healthcare Solutions Inc., Sutherland Government Solutions Inc., Nuevora Inc., Sutherland Global Services New York Inc., SGS USA Inc., Adventity Inc., Sutherland Global Collection Services LLC, Sutherland Mortgage Services Inc., Sutherland Global Services SPV Inc. and Sutherland Global Holdings Inc. participate in and have certified their compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.  We are committed to subjecting all Personal Data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. https://www.privacyshield.gov

Sutherland is responsible for the processing of Personal Data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.  We comply with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of Personal Data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to Personal Data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Sutherland is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. Anent the discussion under the Legal heading above, in certain situations, we may be required to disclose Personal Data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.  

#### Contact Data

Sutherland Data Privacy Office

Attention. Chief Data Privacy Officer

Sutherland Global Services Inc.,

1160 Pittsford Victor Road

Pittsford, NY 14534

privacy@sutherlandglobal.com

#### Changes to This Privacy Policy

You should review this Privacy Policy on a routine basis as Sutherland reserves the right change this Privacy Policy, or any portion thereof, an updated version of our Privacy Policy will be posted to our website.
